### Joseph Nkumah

Flat 25, Room 3, Paddington Park House, Liverpool.
Mobile Number: 07494019836
Whatsapp Number: +2348152667699
Email: josephnkumah97@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

A dedicated and enthusiastic MSc student in Advanced Computer Science. With significant employment and voluntary experience. I can work to a very high standard using my own initiative or as part of the team. Ability to communicate with a variety of people and manage them with my leadership skills.

#### **Education & Qualifications**

Liverpool Hope University, England MSc Advanced Computer Science

January 2022 - Present

Cardiff Metropolitan University, Wales

2017-2019

## **MSc Sports Performance Analysis (Analytics)**

- Developed the ability to integrate software systems with databases.
- Gained knowledge of software system principles.
- Development of writing skills and methodologies through reporting research essays.
- Used sport professional software Nacsport and Sport code to collect sport data for analysis.
- Developed programs and analyzed data using MATLAB.
- Utilized Excel and Tableau for visualization.
- Used SPSS to develop models and predict outcomes.
- Used UCINET and SOCNETV to conduct social network analysis experiments.
- Dissertation project topic: Network Analysis of the top four teams in the English Premier League.

Bingham University, Nigeria

2011-2015

#### **BSc Computer Science (2.1)**

- Dissertation topic: Web Development of a School Football Team.
- Developed the ability to create programs with programming languages such as QBasic,
   Java and C++.
- Designed and managed websites using HTML, PHP, and MySQL.

#### **Employment**

# Web/Software Development Instructor (Part-time) AfriHub, Global Learning Centre

July 2021 - December 2021

- Train students on the fundamentals and advanced Python programming language.
- Guide students on software projects in Python, Database Design and Development, and SQL.
- Teach students how to use Object Oriented Programming (OOP) in Python.

- Teach programming languages such as HTML, CSS and Javascript and SQL.
- Teach backend technology PHP.

# Web Developer

March 2021 - December 2021

Luday

- Use React framework to build front-end web applications.
- Develop cross-platform responsive front-end websites using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Engineer back-end of web applications with Django/Laravel.
- Host web applications on Amazon Web Services.
- Use package managers such as Composer and NPM.
- Use version control through git and BitBucket.
- Implement Agile method to work as a team to develop web and mobile solutions for customers.

## Web/Software Development Instructor(Part-time) El Academy

March 2021- May 2021

- Train students on Python programming language.
- Prepare assessments for improving students' knowledge.
- Relay knowledge of modern programming practices such as Object Oriented Programming (OOP).
- Teach programming languages such as HTML, CSS and Javascript.

#### **Web/Software Development Instructor** El Academy

November 2020-January 2021

- Training and preparing students for internship in El Academy.
- Solve complex problems using Python programming language.
- Relay knowledge of front end and back end development tools to develop individuals in web development.
- Teach programming languages such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and Python to students and develop or improve their programming skills.

#### **Data Scientist (Intern)**

July 2020-August 2020

Hash Analytic, United Kingdom.

- Manage master data set, develop reports, and troubleshoot data issues.
- Remote work with data science professionals to understand data, develop models and predict outcomes.
- Analysis of data to answer complicated questions from data provided.
- Using Python and Tableau to visualize data for excellent presentation.
- Using Machine Learning techniques to train and test models for best fit.

#### **Data Scientist (Intern)**

DataLab, Nigeria.

June 2020-September 2020

- Collected, interpreted & analyzed data to generate insights and forecast based on trends.
- Built algorithms, design experiments, and analyze data to drive optimization and improvement of product development, marketing techniques, and business strategies.
- Assessed the effectiveness and accuracy of new data sources and data gathering techniques.
- Used machine learning tools, predictive modeling, and statistical techniques to produce solutions to problems and optimize business outcomes.
- Identified patterns and trends in data sets.

## **Software Engineer (Intern)**

January 2020-April 2020

NanoMatriX, Hong Kong.

- Assisted in designing and developing high-quality interactive UI for mobile and desktop users.
- Assisted in the developing web and mobile applications.
- Communicated with designers and sales to meet content and functional requirements.
- Program, application testing and implementation.
- Applied and improved best practices in coding and documentation for quality assurance.
- Prepared system documentation and conduct program performance tests to assure optimal
- performance across multiple browsers and operating systems.
- Used AWS services to develop models, train data and carry out deployment.

Assistant lecturer 2015-2016

Federal College of Education (Technical), Nigeria.

- Awarded the Certificate of National Youth Service Corps (NYSC).
- Served as assistant lecturer and taught computer science to students.
- Assisted colleagues with the preparation of test and examination papers.
- Invigilated examinations and was given the responsibility of marking assignments, tests and examination scripts.
- Assisted the Computer Science Head of Department with projects for the faculty.

# **Equipment Supervisor**

2014

Capital FM, 92.9, Nigeria

- A six-month internship at a radio station in my third year of university.
- Given responsibility to supervise equipment used for transmitting signals.
- Assisted colleagues in developing a website for the radio station.

# **Voluntary Work**

**Head Coach** 2017-2019

Cardiff Metropolitan University International Football Team, Wales

- Developed the ability to be a leader as I organize training schedules and prepare the team for games.
- Given the responsibility to coach the International football team of Cardiff Metropolitan University.
- Improvised training drills and programs to aid the team's development.
- Motivated players to improve individually and as a team.

References available on request.